Virgil Hoyt McClintock papers, Inclusive: 1911-1952, undated, Bulk: 1945-1951, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Virgil Hoyt McClintock papers
Inclusive: 1911-1952, undated, Bulk: 1945-1951, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3912
McClintock, Virgil Hoyt
17 document boxes
The Virgil Hoyt McClintock papers contain case files, memoranda, photographs, scrapbooks, books, and other materials relating to V.H. McClintock’s involvement in the judicial review of NAZI War Crime cases.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Poor.
Biography/Profile
V.H. McClintock, as he was commonly known, was born on 1897 September 16 in Coryell, Texas, to Thomas and Anna Garrett McClintock. Little is known about McClintock’s career before or after his tenure in Germany, except that he practiced law in Texas, including some time in Lubbock. He married his first wife, Calla Walker McClintock, and had one daughter, Anna Sue Caswell, before the start of World War II.
McClintock’s work with the War Crimes section was primarily spent reviewing sentences given to convicted NAZI war criminals during the Dachau Trials. The Dachau Trials were the hearings held before the infamous Nuremberg Trials, and were trials for lesser-known NAZIs. McClintock was primarily assigned to review two types of cases, P.O.W. cases (often known as “flyer” cases), and concentration camp cases. The most famous P.O.W. case McClintock reviewed was known as the Malmedy massacre, when over 70 American prisoners of war were killed during the Battle of the Bulge outside of the Belgian town Malmedy by troops of the German First SS Panzer Division. The trial was one of the most-publicized and most controversial of the war, with over 70 defendants and 43 initial death sentences (none of which were ultimately carried out). McClintock was also involved with reviewing cases from various concentration camps, including Mauthausen, Flossenberg, and Nordhausen. Case files, memoranda, and reference materials relating to all of these cases are included in this collection.
Unfortunately, McClintock’s first wife Calla died in the United States on 1956 December 23. He later married a German woman, Elisabeth Gliemann, before the family returned to Texas in 1961. The couple had three children, Elisabeth Umble, William Hoyt McClintock, and John Carey McClintock. Virgil Hoyt McClintock died in Temple, Texas, on 1974 May 3. His papers are an excellent resource for any researcher interested in studying legal history, the Holocaust, or justice during World War II.
Scope and Content
The Virgil Hoyt McClintock papers contain case files, memoranda, photographs, scrapbooks, books, and other materials relating to V.H. McClintock’s involvement in the judicial review of NAZI War Crime cases. Of particular note are a large number of case files containing evidence pertaining to the prosecution and review of numerous sentences, including those related to crimes perpetrated in the Flossenburg Concentration Camp, Mauthausen Concentration Camp, and the P.O.W. “Flyer” cases including the Malmedy Massacre.
Virgil Hoyt McClintock was an attorney with the War Crimes section of the Army Judge Advocate General’s Office (JAG) in Germany in the years following World War II. As a member of the prosecuting legal team, McClintock was responsible for reviewing the sentences of over 100 convicted war criminals after their initial trials concluded. Files from his time in Germany, filled with evidence, photographs, and legal procedures, comprise this collection.
The naming of a defendant in this collection does not imply guilt.
Arrangement
Prior to this finding aid the Virgil Hoyt McClintock papers contained no collection-level organizational scheme. There were a large number of labeled and numbered folders, and their titles have been preserved when possible. There were also a large number of documents that were not in folders and had no apparent organization.
Currently, the collection is organized into six series: I. Case Files, II. Reference Materials, III. Legal Memoranda, IV. Personal, V. Scrapbooks, and VI. Books.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3912. Acquired 2014-04-14
Related Resources
Related references
American-Israeli Cooperative Enterprise. “The Holocaust: NAZI War Crimes Trials.” Jewish Virtual Library. Accessed on 2014 July 3.
"Elisabeth McClintock obituary." Wilkirson Hatch Bailey Funeral Home. Accessed on 2014 July 3.
"Texas, Deaths, 1890-1976," index and images, FamilySearch. Calla L Mcclintock, 1956 December 23; citing certificate number 68214, State Registrar Office, Austin; FHL microfilm 2135192. Accessed on 2014 July 10.
United States Holocaust Memorial Museum. “US Army Trials in Postwar Germany.” Holocaust Encyclopedia. Accessed on 2014 July 3.
Find A Grave, Inc. “Virgil Hoyt McClintock.” Memorial #102922948. Databases. Accessed on 2014 July 10.
Weingartner, James J. Crossroads of Death: The Story of the Malmédy Massacre and Trial. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1979.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945.
Subjects (Organizations)
Flossenbu¨rg (Concentration Camp); Mauthausen (Concentration camp); Nordhausen (Concentration camp)
Places
Germany -- Politics and government -- 1933-1945.
Subjects
Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Law -- Germany -- History.; Lawyers -- Texas.; Malmedy Massacre, 1944-1945.; War crime trials -- Germany -- Dachau.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Prisoners and prisons.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genres
Correspondence.; Financial records.; Legal documents.; Scrapbooks.
- Case Files, 1946-1951, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains case files and legal reviews pertaining to the NAZI war crimes defendants from the Dachau Trials. The case files are organized alphabetically by the defendant’s last name. Case numbers are also included, and should be noted when viewing files of various defendants that were tried in one trial.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Albrecht, Wilhelm: Case No. 12-2000, 1950 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Altena, Friedrich Wilhelm: Case No. 12-1068, 1951 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Blum, Phillipp: Case No. 12-449, 1950 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases" Bodenstein, Julius: Case No. 12-1576, 1951 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Bohrs, Ernst: Case No. 12-531, 1948 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Dammann, Herman: Case No. 12-531, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Gross, Johann: Case No. 12-1109, 1947 July 25-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Gross, Kurt: Case No. 12-43, 1951 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Hauenschild, Harry: Case No. 12-3205, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Heidmann, Gustav: Case No. 12-1422, 1949 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Hermann, Max: Case No. 12-1542, 1947 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Hirschelmann, Walter: Case No. 12-1821, 1951 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Huber, Irmgard: Case No. 12-449, 1951 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Kowitzke, Leo: Case No. 12-1960-1, 1950 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Krein, Matthias: Case No. 12-2422, 1950 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Lippmann, Helmut: Case No. 12-1866, 1951 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Melchior, Johann: Case No. 12-1821, 1951 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Merkle, Adolf: Case No. 12-449, 1950 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Poehla, Fritz: Case No. 12-1745, 1951 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Rudman, Erwin: Case No. 12-1934, 1951 June (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Scherer, Karl Heinz: Case No. 12-2694, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Schnelle, Erich: Case No. 12-1422, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Schraff, Albert and Seibold, Hans: Case No. 12-931, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Spletzer, Rudolf: Case No. 12-43, 1951 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Stieblaichinger, A: Case No. 5-73, 1947 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Steinert, Georg: Case No. 12-494, 1951 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Stredele, Bernhard: Case No. 12-1155-1, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Vogler, Ernst: Case No. 12-1745, 1951 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Wegmann, Richard: Case No. 12-1967, 1951 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Weiss, Franz: Case No. 12-1885, 1950 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Wipperman, Erich: Case No. 12-966, 1951 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Photographs: Case No. 6-24 (1 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Photographs: Case No. 6-24 (2 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: General: Case No. 6-24, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: General: Case No. 6-24, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Bersin, Valentin: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Bode, Friedel: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Briesemeister, Kurt: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Christ, Friedrich: Case No. 6-24, 1949 March (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Diefenthal, Josef: Case No. 6-24, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Goldschmidt, Ernst: Case No. 6-24, 1949 March (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Huber, Hubert: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Ochmann, Paul: Case No. 6-24, 1949 March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Peiper, Joachim: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Preuss, Georg: Case No. 6-24, 1949 March-April (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Rumpf, Erich: Case No. 6-24, 1949 March (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases: Malmedy Massacre: Zwigart, Paul: Case No. 6-24, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mass Atrocity Case: Hadamar Trial: Case No. 12-449, 1946 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Spy Case: Zirlik, Elfriede: Record of Trial, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Camp Cases: Buchenwald: Schmidt, Hans: Case No. 50-9, 1949 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Camp Cases: Buchenwald: zu Waldeck, Josias Prince et al.: Case No. 50-9, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Camp Cases: Dachau: Jergas, Wilhelm: Case No. 50-136, 1949 June 8 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Camp Cases: Dachau: Krech, Stefan: Case No. 59-2-90, 1949 March-April (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Camp Cases: Dachau: Weber, Anton: Case No. 50-2-25, 1949 June 16 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: General, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Auerswald, Max: Case No. Flossenburg-10, 1951 January 16 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Becker, Friedrich: Case No. 59-46-3, 1951 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Bongartz, Peter: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Brusch, Wilhlm: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 8 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Buddensieg, Ludwig: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 9 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Fahrnbauer, August: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Fielder, Albert: Case No. 50-46-2, 1951 February 14 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Fritzsche: Case No. unknown, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Geissberger, Johann: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 17 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Gelhardt, Michael: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 17 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Graeber, Karl: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 20 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Haubold, Gerhard: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 20 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Jakubith, Alois: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 24 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Keiling, Karl: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 27 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Lipinski, Hans: Case No. 50-46, 1950 November 28 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Loesch, Eduard: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Loh, Wilhelm: Case No. 59-46-1, 1950 January 31 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Mathoi, Karl: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Matzke, Gustav: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Maurer, Raimund: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 11 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Neye, Walter: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 8 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Pachen, Hermann: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Pawliczek, Otto: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Penz, Erich: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 18 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Pinter, Josef: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 19 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Reupsch, Walter: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 28 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenbug: Schmaltz, Sepp: Case No. 50-46-3, 1950 February 15 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenbug: Schreiber, Kurt: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 24 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Schubert, Klois: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 23 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Skierka, Bruno: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 23 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Sommerfield, Hermann: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Vican, Johann: Case No. unknown, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Weilbach, Georg: Case No. 50-46, 1950 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Camp Cases: Flossenburg: Wissmann, Edmund: Case No. 50-46-1, 1951 February 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: General, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Billman, Karl: Case No. 50-5, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Bloy, Gustav Hermann Adolf: Case No. unknown, 1950 February 21 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Cserny, Michael: Case No. 50-5, 1946-1950 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Doerr, Ludwig: Case No. 50-5, 1950 March 23 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Erb, Eduard: Case No. unknown, 1950 April 11 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Fenner, Paul: Case No. 50-5-15, 1949 September 6 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Fullgraf, Herbert: Case No. 50-5-13, 1951 April 3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Giese, Heinrich: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Goetz, Kaspar: Case No. 50-5-4, 1950 April 25 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Grzybowski, Herbert: Case No. 50-5, 1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Guenther, Fritz: Case No. 50-5-4, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Guestzlaff, Paul: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Haider, Johann: Case No. 50-5-13, 1951 March 27 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Hirsch, Rudolf: Case No. 50-5-13, 1951 March 30 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Hoehler, Walter: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Kirschbichler, Ernst: Case No. 50-5-22, 1950 March 16 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Koetzle, Otto: Case No. 50-5-15, 1950 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Kopischke, Otto: Case No. 50-5-4, 1951 March 20 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Korger, Viktor: Case No. 50-5-4, 1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Kroner, Johann: Case No. 50-5-2, 1950 March 7 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Lappert, Ferdinand: Case No. 50-5, 1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Lehrbacher: Case No. unknown, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Mack, Wilhelm: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Mayer, Josef: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Meyer, Ernst: Case No. 50-5-4, 1951 March 19 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Mussfeldt, Erich: Case No. unknown, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Nitschke, Fritz: Case No. 50-5-2, 1951 March 6 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Rutka, Adolf: Case No. 50-5, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Sturm, Hermann: Case No. 50-5-41, 1948 February 26 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Camp Cases: Mauthausen: Wolfram, Paul: Case No. 50-5-49, 1950 April 5 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Andrae, Arthur: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Brauny, Erhard: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Brinkmann, Otto: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Detmers, Heinrich: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Helbig, Oskar: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Jacobi, Rudolf: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Killian, Josef: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Koenig, Georg: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Ruekrina: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Ulbricht, Walter: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Walenta, Richard: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Camp Cases:Nordhausen: Zweiner, Willi: Dora Trial, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Dora Trial: Photographs (1 of 4), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Dora Trial: Photographs (2 of 4), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Dora Trial: Photographs (3 of 4), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Camp Cases: Nordhausen: Dora Trial: Photographs (4 of 4), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, 1946 September (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, 1946 October (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1946 November (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Reviews, 1946 December (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 1946 January (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Reviews, 1946 February (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Reviews, 1946 March 5-26 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, 1946 March 27-April 8 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, 1946 June-July (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1947 August (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, 1947 September (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Reviews, 1947 October (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, 1947 November (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, 1947 December (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1948 January (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Reviews, 1948 February-March (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 1948 April (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Reviews, 1948 May 3-21 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Reviews, 1948 May 25-31 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, 1948 June (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, 1948 July (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Reviews, 1948 August (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Reviews, 1948 September (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1948 October (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, 1948 November-1949 January (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reviews: Buchenwald, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reviews: Dachau (1 of 2), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reviews: Dachau (2 of 2), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reviews: P.O.W. "Flyer" Cases, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Reviews: Italy, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Reviews: Mauthausen, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Reviews: Muehldof, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Reviews: Shanghai, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - War Crime Review Instructions, 1949-1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Reference Materials, 1911-1951, undated; 2
  This series contains printed materials containing official information regarding V.H. McClintock’s job as a member of the War Crimes section.
  - Inmate Lists, 1947 July 30 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Inmate Lists, 1950 May 15 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Inmate Lists, 1951 January 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Inmate Lists, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - German Language Course Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Blank Forms, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Notes and Drafts, 1947-1950, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Printed Materials, 1946 March-July 13 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials, 1946 July 15 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Printed Materials, 1946 July 26-December (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials, 1946 December (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials, 1947 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials, 1947 August-September (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials, 1947 October 6-13 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Printed Materials, 1947 November (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials, 1947 December-1948 February (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Printed Materials: "Survey of the Trials of War Crimes Held at Dachau Germany", 1948 September 14 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Printed Materials, 1950 April, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Published Materials: "Military Tribunals and Their Jurisdiction", 1911 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Published Materials: "Courts-Martial and the Laws of War", 1923 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Published Materials: "Punishment of Offenders Against the Laws and Customs of War" by James W. Garner, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Published Materials: "Military Government Regulations", circa 1946 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Published Materials: "Military Government Regulations", 1947 March 27 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Published Materials: "United States v. Jürgen Stroop et al: Review and Recommendations", 1947 September 2 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Published Materials: "Manual of Civil Affairs Military Government", 1947 October (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Published Materials: "United States v. Josias Prince zu Waldeck et al: Review and Recommendations", 1947 November 15 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Published Materials: "Malmedy Massacre Investigation: Report of Subcommittee on Armed Services United States Senate", 1949 October 13 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Published Materials: Texas Bar Journal, 1950 February-April (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Published Materials: Revue Universitaire Suisse (Academic Journal of Switzerland), 1950 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Published Materials: Federal Register Part II, 1951 February 10 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Published Materials: Palast Hotel Brochure, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)